

Hello

I'm Anilkumar Reddy

SAP Certified Commerce Cloud Developer https://www.youracclaim.com/users/anilkumar.reddy

Email anilkreddy.a@gmail.com

Mobile +91 9900606018

Web https://anil.red

Address Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Hello! I'm Anil. Senior Developer specialized in Java/J2ee, Spring, SAP CX and JavaScript. Experienced with all stages of development life cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including Java, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, HTML. Strong background in project management and customer relations

6+ years of experience in developing highly transactional eCommerce web applications within an agile environment using SAP Commerce Cloud and J2EE technologies. Having understood of spring framework, design patterns and object-oriented concepts. Playing a proactive role in performing requirement analysis and converting requirements into working software by designing, developing and testing across various projects. Interacted with business, functional and technical representatives of project teams to analyse system requirements. Quick learner, possesses excellent problemsolving skills, communication skills and a strong team player.







<u>Professional Summary</u>

- Development experience in wide area of modules such as Wishlist, OCC, Authentication, WCMS, CronJobs, Impex, Flexible Search Query, Web Services, Order Management, Backoffice, PCM Backoffice, Cybersource and Braintree payment integrations, Google product integrations.
- Integration experience with SAP ERP backend systems.
- Experienced in working with the Agile development methodology. Familiar with all the Agile ceremonies and working in a sprint cycle.
- Experienced in performing requirement analysis and solution development.
- Hands on development experience of Spring MVC design pattern.
- Development knowledge of frontend technologies like HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, CSS, Ajax.
- Experienced using tools such as SonarQube, Eclipse, SourceTree, Amazon S3, Git.
- Experience on Hsql, Oracle 11g R2 & MySQL databases.
- Experience using Atlassian products like Confluence, JIRA, Bitbucket.
- Hands on experience of integrating REST & SOAP web services.
- Working knowledge of using various services in AWS and hands on experience on different Cloud providers.

Awards and Achievements

- Spot Light Award Cognizant, June 2019.
- Milestone Award, 3 years Sonata Software, August 2017.
- Nominated for Innovation and Process Excellence Award Sonata Software, December 2016.
- Quarterly award for Customer and Business Excellence Sonata Software, January 2016.
- DNA Award, Run for It Sonata Software, September 2015.
- DNA Award, Everyone Counts Sonata Software, August 2015.
- Best Outgoing Student Acharya Institute of Technology, May 2014.

Technical Skills

Programming	Java/J2EE, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, TypeScript
Languages	
Frameworks &	SAP Hybris, Spring framework, Ionic Framework,
Platforms	Codelgniter, Laravel
Databases	HSQLdb, MySQL, Oracle, SAP HANA
Tools & IDEs	Eclipse, Git, Bitbucket, WinSCP, Putty, VSCode

Frontend	HTML,	CSS,	JavaScript,	jQuery,	Bootstrap,
	Angular				

Work Experience

Sr. Developer – EAS SAP

Apr 2018 - Present

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Bengaluru

Senior Systems Analyst

Aug 2014 - Mar 2018

Sonata Software Limited, Bengaluru

Education

BE – Computer Science and Engineering

2010 - 2014

Acharya Institute of Technology, Bengaluru

Class XII - PCMCs

2008 - 2010

SBGNS Rural Composite PU College, Chikkaballapura

Class X
Govt. Junior College, Bagepalli, Chikkaballapura

2005 - 2008

Projects

Client: Johnson & Johnson

About:

Johnson & Johnson is an American multinational medical devices, pharmaceutical and consumer packaged goods manufacturing company founded in 1886. Its common stock is a component of the Dow Jones Industrial Average and the company is listed among the Fortune 500.

Johnson & Johnson is headquartered in New Brunswick, New Jersey, the consumer division being located in Skillman, New Jersey. The corporation includes some 250 subsidiary companies with operations in 60 countries and products sold in over 175 countries. Johnson & Johnson had worldwide sales of \$70.1 billion during calendar year 2015. The company has made the 3rd largest pharmaceutical settlement with the U.S. Department of Justice.

9: JJ Customer Connect (NA & EMEA) - OCC

Team Size	4
Duration	March 2020 - Present
Hybris	SAP Hybris v6.7
Roles & Responsibilities	 As part of the global innovation program, exposed custom B2B OCC APIs in NA and EMEA regions. Worked on Customer master and Materials master APIs to expose products and b2b units via REST APIs to third parties. Implemented multi region order related APIs (Validate Cart, Create Order, Order Details and Order History) Setting up APIs in Apigee Edge and created proxies for different environments and regions.

8: JJ Surgical Vision - B2B Store

o. JJ Surgical Vis	
URL	https://us-vision.jjcustomerconnect.com
Team Size	7
Duration	January 2019 – February 2020
Hybris	SAP Hybris v6.7
Roles & Responsibilities	 Attending business grooming sessions and understanding the requirements. Participated in discussions with client to clarify stories. Integration with SAP for data loads. Implementing integrations using SOAP to communicate with SAP system for price enquiry, order creation, Inventory adjustment, automated user registration. Working on Inventory management – Return Inventory, Process Inventory & Manage Inventory. Customizing backoffice widgets as per business needs. Setting up the Content and Product Catalogs. Writing data feed jobs to load data from Staging tables (intermediate tables b/w ERP & Hybris) Automating the customer registration journey with ERP system. Implementing the sales rep functionalities – Sales Rep Inventory, Trail Pricing, Impersonation.

7: JJ Surgical Vision - OCC

7. 33 Saigicat Vis	<u> </u>
URL	https://us-vision.jjcustomerconnect.com
Team Size	3
Duration	July 2018 – December 2018
Hybris	SAP Hybris v6.7
Roles &	Attending business grooming sessions and understanding
Responsibilities	the requirements.

•	a compared in a second to with other to startly stories.
•	Implementing OCC services to be consumed by mobile app development team.

6: JJ Customer Connect - Notification Preferences

URL	https://us.jjcustomerconnect.com
Team Size	3
Duration	April 2018 – June 2018
Hybris	SAP Hybris v6.0
Roles & Responsibilities	 Understanding the requirements to enhance current notification preferences. Adding new notification types. Implemented text message for notifications. Integrated SMS Engine to send notification SMS. Written cronjobs to send the email and SMS notifications. UI changes to Notification preferences sections of Registration and My profile pages.

Client: TUI UK & Ireland About:

TUI Group is the world's number one tourism business. From now on, the broad portfolio gathered under the Group umbrella will consist of strong tour operators, 1,600 travel agencies and leading online portals, six touristic airlines with around 150 aircraft, over 300 hotels with 214,000 beds, 16 cruise liners and countless incoming agencies in all major holiday destinations around the globe. This integrated offering will enable us to provide our 20 million customers with an unmatched holiday experience in 180 regions. A key feature of our corporate culture is our global responsibility for economic, environmental and social sustainability.

5: Elasticsearch Integration

J. Etastiosoaroi i	<u> </u>
URL	https://www.tui.co.uk
Team Size	6
Duration	August 2017 – March 2018
Hybris	SAP Hybris v6.4
Roles & Responsibilities	 Understanding the current system with endeca as search solution.
	 Replacement of endeca with elasticsearch solution. Created a highly customizable cronjob to export data to elastic server.

4: Hybris platform upgradation

URL	https://www.tui.co.uk
Team Size	4
Duration	June 2017 – July 2017
Hybris	SAP Hybris v5.5 & v6.4
Roles & Responsibilities	 Hybris upgradation from 5.5 to 6.4. Understanding the current functionalities of all the brands. Fixing upgrade build issues and migrating code. Fixing regression test defects raised by internal test team. Updating dependencies like third party integrations and services.

Client: Pillowtalk Australia Pty Ltd.

About:

Pillow Talk is 100% Australian owned and operated and one of the largest home linens specialists in the country. We started from humble beginnings with one small store in Brisbane's Ann Street back in 1977 and have continued to grow into a well-regarded household name that is the first port-of-call for many Australians. Pillow Talk is an Omni-channel operator providing our customers both a visual journey via our 57 stores around the country, as well as a convenient Online and mobile store.

As specialists in industry, Pillowtalk carry on average over 300 different cushion designs across a myriad of color ways and textures. Pillowtalk is home to more than 90 different pillows, 300-400 quilt cover designs as well as sheets in all varying qualities and thread counts.

3: Production Support for Pillowtalk B2C Webstore

URL	https://www.pillowtalk.com.au	
Team Size	2	
Duration	September 2015 – May 2017	
Hybris	SAP Hybris v5.4	
Roles &	Bug fixing for production environment.	
Responsibilities	 Understanding of requirements and developing solutions and implementing them for Change Requests. 	

Migrated payment gateway from Cybersource to Braintree.
Replaced Exact Target(Salesforce EDM) with
Emarsys(Marketing Cloud).
 Customized PDP as per the client requirements.
Worked on Store finder module.
 Integration of Crazy Egg tracking into Hybris.
Worked on custom reports in report cockpit.
 Moved checkout process from multi-step to single page checkout.
Integrated Afterpay payment solution.
Implemented multiple wish lists.
Preparing build files for UAT and Production environments.
Worked on release management.

2: Pillowtalk B2C Webstore

LIDI Jatha ay / /www.waillawshall (a a sa a u	
URL	https://www.pillowtalk.com.au
Team Size	15
Duration	January 2015 – August 2015
Hybris	SAP Hybris v5.4
Roles & Responsibilities	 Developing User Stories relating to various modules of Hybris. Understanding of requirements and developing solutions and implementing them. Worked on Wishlist customizations. Worked on Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager and Google Merchant Center integrations. Integrated SDL Fredhopper in place of Solr. Experian QAS integration for Address validations. Worked on forms customization, validation using jQuery and Java Validator. Involved in Cybersource payment gateway integration with multi-step checkout process. Worked on customizing the SEO/SEM. Customization of home page using WCMS components along with Fredhopper campaigns. Worked on integration system for product and stock import from ERP system. Implemented Gift Card as a special product. Creating components, content slots, page templates through impex. Involved in bug fixing.

1: Muse by Pillowtalk home store

211 1000 by 1 120 W Cati (1101110 Store	
URL	www.musebypillowtalk.com.au
Team Size	3
Duration	November 2014 – January 2015
Hybris	SAP Hybris v4.7

Roles & Responsibilities

- Creating an extra storefront using multiple content catalogs.
- Involved in customizing the CMS content.
- Creating component, content slots and page templates based on the requirements.
- Customization of UI based on the wireframes.
- Created new content catalog.